<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aiyumi.Github.Io</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/</link><description>Accessibility, audio, games, Linux and other things, from the point of view of a visually impaired.</description><atom:link href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/rss.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 Aiyumi &lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/"&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 23:45:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Changed the Website's Layout at Last!</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/changed-layout-at-last/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;9 years later - yes, the blog started in 2011 -, I finally got around to changing the website's layout! The new layout is based on the &lt;a href="https://themes.getnikola.com/v7/yesplease/"&gt;Yesplease theme for the Nikola CMS&lt;/a&gt; with lots of modifications. It's a very barebones layout, but hopefully the text is easier to read. Unlike the previous layout, this one is responsive and should work better on small screens like on smartphones and tablets. Now the content is on the right, the menu is on the left and should be toggleable on small screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still intend to continue publishing most of my posts on the &lt;a href="https://hive.blog/@aiyumi"&gt;Hive social network&lt;/a&gt;, so I embedded the feed showing the links to my latest Hive posts on the main page. The only problem is that I had to use JavaScript for that (there was no other way because this is static site and has no support for any programming language like PHP), and nothing will change for those who use browsers with no JavaScript support (just visit my Hive profile page and view my posts there directly, just like it was before). I believe this shouldn't be much of a problem, though...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another improvement was in the post listing pages. Now these pages show a brief snippet of the posts, rather than only the title like it used to be. This applies both to the normal blog posts and the Hive posts on the front page! The listings should be more interesting this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: too early to celebrate, it seems. When I uploaded the files to the server, the Hive feed didn't load. Apparently, browsers don't like that this blog on GitHub Pages is HTTPS and the feed site is HTTP (the feed's download gets blocked with a "mixed content" error). I contacted one of the &lt;a href="https://hiverss.com/"&gt;feed site&lt;/a&gt;'s maintainers and asked if HTTPS could be added via a free service, and they said they'll look into it some time later this week. I'll update this post once the issue gets resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit (2020/10/28): solved! HTTPS was added to HiveRSS, and the feed embed on the main page works now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is it for this update. See you in my next posts, either on Hive or on here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/changed-layout-at-last/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:36:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Time to Say Goodbye to the Warpstar.net Domain</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/goodbye-to-the-warpstar/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was alerted that the "warpstar.net" domain is going to expire if I don't renew the registration until May 13th, 2020. I get these alert messages every year, when it's one month from the domain registration anniversary. A few years ago, I had already &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/static-blog-migration"&gt;canceled the paid webhosting plan that was getting quite expensive to me&lt;/a&gt;, and this year, I decided it's time to let the paid domain go. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/goodbye-to-the-warpstar/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/goodbye-to-the-warpstar/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 23:41:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Status Update 2019/07/21</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/status-update-2019-07-21/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot has already happened in this year of 2019:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year's first half was particularly hard. My mother got sick, and we went through some tough times. For a few months, I had no time nor inspiration and wasn't in the mood to post anything anywhere, and sadly had to put my violin lessons on hold as well. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/status-update-2019-07-21/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/status-update-2019-07-21/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 23:43:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Two New Toys in the Kitchen</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/two-new-toys-in-the-kitchen/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/p3-food-ramen"&gt;post about ramen&lt;/a&gt;, I had talked about some of the obstacles I face in the kitchen, and that cooking isn't my cup of tea. But as evidenced by that post itself, sometimes crazy things happen when I decide to do something different... &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/two-new-toys-in-the-kitchen/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/two-new-toys-in-the-kitchen/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 23:42:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Small Status Update and a Post About Accessibility of Clickable HTML Elements</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/status-update-2018-07-20/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just passing by to show I'm still around :P . It's been a few months since I last posted anything here, but I still update my fan fiction every month. To my surprise, I've also been managing to be active on Steemit, posting at least once a week (twice if we consider I usually publish the same post both in Portuguese and in English). Incidentally, my last Steemit post was about the accessibility problems that happen a lot with clickable HTML objects, which may be of interest to anyone visiting my blog to read about accessibility. Below is the link to the post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://steemit.com/accessibility/@aiyumi/web-accessibility-clickable-objects-and-screen-readers"&gt;Web Accessibility - Clickable Objects and Screen Readers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find other posts on &lt;a href="https://steemit.com/@aiyumi"&gt;my Steemit blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/status-update-2018-07-20/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 17:35:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Keyboards and Demo Songs</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/keyboard-demo-songs/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far, I have owned three musical keyboards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A basic Casio which I don't remember the model anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Fenix TG-8880D (Brazilian brand). It looked like a piano from outside, but its sounds and features weren't that impressive...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And the Yamaha Motif XF, which is a beast (in a good way :P ).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The former two aren't here anymore, but the XF has been with me for seven years (I've already posted music arrangements using it here on the blog quite a few times). It has sounds that I like a lot, and many features I still haven't been able to master!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the time I owned my first keyboard, I've always liked to listen to the demo songs. A few days ago, I wrote a post talking a bit about my keyboards and my appreciation for demo songs, also with some links for listening to demos of the Fenix keyboard, as well as a link to a Youtube channel I found with demos of a lot of other keyboards. I published the post on Steemit, and you can check it out on the link below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://steemit.com/music/@aiyumi/keyboards-and-my-addiction-to-demo-songs"&gt;Keyboards and My "Addiction" to Demo Songs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/keyboard-demo-songs/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 01:26:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Watch the Persona 5 Anime Online and for Free</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/watch-the-p5-anime/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game Persona 5 which I've been talking about so much got an anime adaptation! It's called "Persona 5 the Animation" and began airing in Japan on April 7th, 2018. And just like what happened to the &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/watch-p5-db-online"&gt;Day Breakers special episode&lt;/a&gt;, the streaming site &lt;a href="http://www.crunchyroll.com/"&gt;Crunchyroll&lt;/a&gt; is simulcasting (streaming the episodes right after they air in Japan), one episode each week, and even with English and Portuguese subtitles! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/watch-the-p5-anime/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Games</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/watch-the-p5-anime/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 22:06:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How Persona 5 Sparked My Interest in the World of Coffee</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/p5-coffee/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Let Me Explain!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not the first time that a game from the Persona series makes me go out of my way to learn something new. The game Persona 3 even made me &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/p3-food-ramen"&gt;try to prepare ramen&lt;/a&gt; even though cooking isn't my thing. Now, it's Persona 5's turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Persona 5, while acting just like a normal student during the day and fighting injustice and corrupt people at night, the young protagonist is forced to live in the attic in a coffee shop, and one of the activities to get items for missions is learning to prepare a good cup of coffee. But it isn't just any coffee! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/p5-coffee/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (8 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Games</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/p5-coffee/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 19:05:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Slint, a Slackware-Based Linux Distribution that's Accessible to the Visually Impaired</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/slint-linux-review/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As some already know, my Linux distribution of choice is Slackware. However, it isn't an easy distro for visually impaired users to install. The Slackware installer isn't accessible unless the users have a hardware-based voice synthesizer (I don't have one, and most others probably also don't), which means they'd need sighted assistance to install it and then install the screen readers. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/slint-linux-review/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (8 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>linux</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/slint-linux-review/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 18:02:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>My First Week on Steemit, and My First Impressions</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/steemit-first-impressions/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've never had much patience, nor luck, with social networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've tried to use twitter, but nothing came out of it. I didn't have the patience to read others' things and post constantly, and it was cumbersome to rephrase everything I wrote to fit the character limit. In the end, &lt;a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/aiyumi_en"&gt;my Twitter&lt;/a&gt; was relegated to just informing people about blog and fanfic updates. &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/steemit-first-impressions/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/steemit-first-impressions/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 13:47:03 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>