<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Aiyumi.Warpstar.Net (Posts about Fan-Made)</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/tag/fan-made.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 15:40:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Persona 5 Opening - UTAU Cover</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/p5-op-utau-cover/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I mentioned &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/getting-ready-for-persona5"&gt;how I was excited about the release of the game Persona 5&lt;/a&gt;. I had been so excited that I began writing fanfictions about it months before the game had even come out in Japan and we had nearly no information about the characters or the setting. On September 15, 2016, the game was released in Japan (I'm writing this on September 15, 2017. So, it was exactly one year ago! :D ). And on April 4, 2017, the western version finally came out (and even had a Japanese audio option as free DLC, like I had wanted).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually don't preorder games, but with Persona 5, I couldn't resist. I got it from an online games store from my country. I traded in two old GBA games I had lying around which I had barely touched (they came with the second-hand GBA I had bought at the end of 2008), and the store gave me an additional discount for paying in full (in the end, the total discount amounted to around R$91 BRL, roughly $30 USD). The store shipped the product quickly, and the game was in my hands on release day (April 7th here in Brazil, unlike North America and Europe that got it on April 4th).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn't say that the game has no flaws, but it was as great and fun as I had expected. I've already beaten it twice (with Japanese audio) and gotten the Platinum trophy in my second playthrough. I'm currently on my third playthrough (trying out the English audio). There are many small details that can easily go unnoticed in the first, or even the second playthrough. Persona 5 continues entertaining me even now, even though it's my third time going through it (and giving me even more fanfic ideas :P ). I'm very satisfied, and glad that it lived up to all the excitement I had since last year. The game is worth every cent, plus the work I went through to trade in the used GBA cartridges :D .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To celebrate platinuming the game, as well as finishing one of my &lt;a href="http://archiveofourown.org/works/7667629"&gt;long fanfictions&lt;/a&gt; (that I began writing before the games Japanese release last year), I did an UTAU cover of the game's opening song, "Wake Up, Get Up, Get Out There." UTAU? Yes, a singing sinthesis software. I've already talked about it &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/accessibility-and-how-i-began-using-vocaloid"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, where I had come to the conclusion that it was unusable without a mouse and I wouldn't be able to use it ever. I was wrong! I suddenly decided to tamper with the program again a few months back, and what was my surprise when I managed to connect a few syllables smoothly! So, I decided to do a cover, and here it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link to the video is below, featuring... the Brasilian version of the game's cover art! (there's stuff written in Portuguese, but the game is in English) ... And a (probably very inaccurate) instrumental made by me, using the accompaniment generator software &lt;a href="http://www.mellowood.ca/mma/"&gt;MMA (Musical MIDI Accompaniment)&lt;/a&gt; and my Motif XF keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credits and more details are in the video description, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ihhnxkKJ8e8"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get the audio only:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="https://od.lk/d/122177959_VkyiM/wake-up_0.1.ogg"&gt;wake-up_0.1.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.4shared.com/mp3/EqnHv6Yqca/wake-up_01.html"&gt;wake-up_0.1.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><category>UTAU</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/p5-op-utau-cover/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 21:16:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rockman DASH - "We are the Three Bonne Brothers" Violin Arrangements</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-2/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those who have read my &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/gossec-gavotte-fvl-cover"&gt;other&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/virtual-violins"&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt; probably noticed that I'm currently obsessed with violins. It turns out that I couldn't resist and, in march of 2015, I began taking lessons to learn to play the real thing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three months have passed, and I continue my &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-1"&gt;arrangements of the song "We Are the Three Bonne Brothers"&lt;/a&gt; from Rockman DASH/Mega Man Legends. Today I bring a few more versions, this time with violins, both the virtual one and the real one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These where made for my fan fiction, "&lt;a href="https://www.fanfiction.net/s/10564022/1/Trigger-of-Change"&gt;Trigger of Change&lt;/a&gt;," where the Servbots learn to play the violin. The piano is the same as the &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-1"&gt;"Marimbonnes" version&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the virtual one, made with the Embertone Friedlander Violin VST.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/101759890_xIo2h_d1b5/bonnes-fvl01.ogg"&gt;bonnes-fvl01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/wxHz8p3Qba/bonnes-fvl01.html"&gt;bonnes-fvl01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is my attempt at playing it with a real violin. Warning: beginner level playing (just three months of taking weekly lessons), and the intonation is still quite off. Also, it's my first time trying to record an acoustic instrument (recorded with a Zoom H4n portable recorder).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/101759900_0s6x3_4a1d/bonnes-realviolin01.ogg"&gt;bonnes-realviolin01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/MJN7Xw8xce/bonnes-realviolin01.html"&gt;bonnes-realviolin01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three violins version: until I arrived at the final result above, I had to record the song over twenty times! I didn't want so many takes to go to waste, so I selected the better three of my recording (mis)takes and glued them together. The result is a trio of clumsy and out of tune Servbots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/101759905_WOe2Z_98a6/bonnes-threeviolins01.ogg"&gt;bonnes-threeviolins01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/4mLQhgynba/bonnes-threeviolins01.html"&gt;bonnes-threeviolins01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three violins + Friedlander Violin version: the "trio" above playing along with the virtual one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/101759911_UKCuo_6679/bonnes-threeviolins-and-fvl01.ogg"&gt;bonnes-threeviolins-and-fvl01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/FPJoQfbgba/bonnes-threeviolins-and-fvl01.html"&gt;bonnes-threeviolins-and-fvl01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><category>Violin</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-2/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 21:35:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rockman DASH - "We are the Three Bonne Brothers" Keyboard Arrangements</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-1/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are my keyboard arrangements of the song "We are the Three Bonne Brothers", also known as the theme song for the Bonnes, the charismatic air pirates from the Rockman DASH/Mega Man Legends series. Performed and recorded on a Yamaha Motif XF keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piano and flute version (shorter): &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/99499160_o5e2n_d694/bonne-brothers01.ogg"&gt;bonne-brothers01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/e5QxhGKVce/bonne-brothers01.html"&gt;bonne-brothers01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piano and flute version (longer): &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/99826482_d2ohR_366c/bonne-brothers02.ogg"&gt;bonne-brothers02.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/E2BgnW5Wba/bonne-brothers02.html"&gt;bonne-brothers02.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update (2015/04/17): piano and marimba version: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/99952953_GaPC6_61a8/marimbonnes01.ogg"&gt;marimbonnes01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/1I8IVJhPce/marimbonnes01.html"&gt;marimbonnes01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-1/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 12:33:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Gossec Gavotte - Friedlander Violin Cover</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/gossec-gavotte-fvl-cover/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/virtual-violins"&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I wrote how I chose the &lt;a href="http://embertone.com/instruments/friedlanderviolin.php"&gt;Embertone Friedlander Violin&lt;/a&gt; virtual instrument to try to fill my violin sound needs, and how I got it to run on Linux. I'm feeling like the protagonist of the anime/game series Kin'iro no Corda (also known as La Corda d'Oro), who is given a magical violin that anyone can play! To "celebrate," I decided to make arrangements of the music featured in the series (mostly classical music), and today I bring you my first one: the "Gavotte" by François Joseph Gossec.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/92820660_MvJaZ_3051/gavotte-fvl-solo_0.1.ogg"&gt;OGG (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/1ThO5eTaba/gavotte-fvl-solo_01.html"&gt;MP3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ywTwzGnvSXw"&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Violin</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/gossec-gavotte-fvl-cover/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 23:57:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>In the Mood to DASH!</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-dash/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I began revisiting the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mega_Man_Legends"&gt;Rockman DASH (Mega Man Legends)&lt;/a&gt; series, watching (read "listening") some playthroughs and cutscenes to refresh my memory (I don't have the games anymore), trying to finally understand the plot. I didn't know enough of either Japanese or English to be able to grasp it at the time I played, which was some 12 years ago. Turns out that I can't fully figure it out even now :P. I have the impression that the second game (the one with the major plot points) felt a bit rushed, some important things are mentioned only in passing and aren't expanded anywhere. After the cancellation of DASH/Legends 3, it's unlikely that we'll be seeing these answers anytime soon. I also noticed differences between the dialogue from the English version and the original Japanese (inconsistencies in the translation/usage of names and terms) which may affect how we view a characters personality, as well as parts of the plot itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from that, I still think it's a good plot, albeit a bit confusing and full of unexplored potential. That calls to one thing: fan fiction!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After checking the playthroughs, then reading a few discussions and fan fictions to see how other people interpret the plot, I was inspired to write my own fanfic, intitled "&lt;a href="https://www.fanfiction.net/s/10564022/1/Trigger-of-Change"&gt;Trigger of Change&lt;/a&gt;". And like I did with my &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/pokemon/sl/drama"&gt;Pokemon fic&lt;/a&gt;, I began making Japanese anime style audio dramas out of it. This prompted the creation of a new &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/rockman"&gt;Rockman section&lt;/a&gt; on the site, with the page for the audio dramas &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/rockman/toc/drama"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude this post, I leave you with my VOCALOID cover of "Anata no Kaze ga Fuku Kara", the ending song to the first game. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/89882897_wjfA3_acdc/gumi_power_-_dash-kaze_0.1.ogg"&gt;OGG (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/44Pq_-xLba/gumi_power_-_dash-kaze_01.html"&gt;MP3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zW77ScDa3hA"&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aiyumi, DASHing off!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><category>Site Updates</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-dash/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 18:51:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Pokemon Section</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/new-pokemon-section/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I added a new Pokemon section to the site, mostly to publish my music arrangements and the fan fic based audio dramas I already &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/twitter-and-updates"&gt;mentioned&lt;/a&gt;. To visit it, go &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/pokemon"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><category>Site Updates</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/new-pokemon-section/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 23:54:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Twitter and Updates</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/twitter-and-updates/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It may not seem like it, but a lot happened after my last post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did an arrangement of another music from Pokemon Black &amp;amp; White. It's the music titled "Ghetsis' Ambitions". Listen &amp;amp; download &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5eUh9bHd7aM"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://gobblin.se/u/aiyumi/m/pokemon-bw-arrange-of-ghetsis-ambitions-motif-xf/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably this is where I'm most active at the moment. I never mentioned it here before, but for some time now, I've been writing a Pokemon Black &amp;amp; White fan fiction (in English). It's called &lt;a href="http://www.fanfiction.net/s/8853146/1/"&gt;Soul Link&lt;/a&gt;, and I'm silently updating it regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did an audio drama adaptation of a scene from said fan fiction. The fanfic is in English, but the audio drama is in Japanese. The dialogue is mostly the same as the one from the fan fiction, so for those who understood the scene in the fic, the Japanese drama can probably be understood as well. A few people who like watching anime with Japanese audio might like it... Or not :P. Anyway, it can be found &lt;a href="https://gobblin.se/u/aiyumi/m/psl-ch004-true-plans/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It also uses the music arrangement I just mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I uploaded a few more sounds to &lt;a href="http://www.freesound.org/people/Aiyumi/"&gt;Freesound&lt;/a&gt;. I also added a lot of interesting sounds from other people to my &lt;a href="http://www.freesound.org/people/Aiyumi/bookmarks/"&gt;bookmarks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally got around to organizing my SlackBuilds for compiling Orca under Slackware and &lt;a href="https://github.com/aiyumi/slackware-scripts"&gt;uploaded them to Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit (2013-09-27): instructions on how to use the scripts now can be found &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/installing-orca-on-slackware-14-0"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a 3DS XL. I wasn't thinking on doing that yet, but once again, I found a cheap one (for Brazil standards), and since prices in general are rising due to inflation, I decided to do it before it got too expensive. I won't make a full review like I did with the other one, but it suffices to say that compared to the normal 3DS, the buttons are more comfortable, the console is easier to hold (though a bit heavier) and the battery lasts more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In mid July, my internet connection stayed down for nearly two weeks, affecting my work and everything. Calling the ISP only resulted in pointless excuses most of the time, and it took very long for them to have the will to send a technician here and fix it. It was a problem affecting the whole region where I live. Hopefully it's sorted out now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I've been listening a lot of Japanese music which uses singing synthesis software like &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vocaloid"&gt;VOCALOID&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Utau"&gt;UTAU&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, a lot happened, as you can see. The problem is that I don't have the patience to write a full blog post for each thing I do, let alone in three languages... And I realized: isn't that the purpose of a microblog like Twitter? Right now, my Twitter isn't seeing much use aside from automatically alerting when I post something here. I'm thinking of making it update (preferably automatically) whenever I publish a fanfic chapter, or a Youtube video and maybe a few other things, so people can know I'm still active even if this blog isn't updated so often. The account is "&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/aiyumi_en"&gt;@aiyumi_en&lt;/a&gt;". You can follow me, or if you're like me and aren't much into these social network things, you can use this &lt;a href="http://www.rssitfor.me/getrss?name=aiyumi_en"&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><category>Site Updates</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/twitter-and-updates/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 18:39:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pokemon BW - Team Plasma's Theme Arrangement</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/plasma-theme-arrange-1/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I did an arrangement of Team Plasma's theme music, from the games Pokemon Black &amp;amp; White. It was performed and recorded on a Yamaha Motif XF keyboard. Here's a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6W5HjQ5MqKQ"&gt;Youtube link&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/69370448_zJzxx_2b49/plasma_0.2.ogg"&gt;download in OGG format&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/plasma-theme-arrange-1/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 02:08:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rockman Fan Fiction</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/rockman-fanfics-01/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I've finally started publishing a fan fiction about the Rockman (Mega Man) series that was sitting here for a long time. It's in Portuguese, but if you want to check it out, you can click &lt;a href="http://www.fanfiction.net/s/7589624/1/Megaman-X-Real-Life"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: exactly today (december 17th, 2011), the series and the blue robot carrying the same name turn twenty four years old! Happy birthday, Rockman!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Fan-Made</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/rockman-fanfics-01/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 17:36:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kirby: Revenge of Error Knight</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/kirby-revenge-of-error-knight/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've never thought that Windows errors could be so interesting. On &lt;a href="http://topicscollector.blog55.fc2.com/blog-entry-4870.html"&gt;this page (in Japanese)&lt;/a&gt;, I've found the video below, where someone plays the theme song of "Revenge of Meta Knight" (from the Kirby series' games), with only the sounds of the Windows error messages!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video begins with the system logon. Then, a program is executed and triggers a sequence of errors to form the music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attention: the video's creator warns you to get away from the screen while watching, because the video shows lots of flashing error messages that may be bad for the eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://ext.nicovideo.jp/thumb_watch/sm6723139"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can't see the video or just prefer to listen, here is only the &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/81156190_iWkW8/error-knight.ogg"&gt;sound in OGG format&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/kirby-revenge-of-error-knight/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 18:01:14 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>