<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aiyumi.Warpstar.Net (Posts about Games)</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/tag/games.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 22:24:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Watch the Persona 5 Anime Online and for Free</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/watch-the-p5-anime/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game Persona 5 which I've been talking about so much got an anime adaptation! It's called "Persona 5 the Animation" and began airing in Japan on April 7th, 2018. And just like what happened to the &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/watch-p5-db-online"&gt;Day Breakers special episode&lt;/a&gt;, the streaming site &lt;a href="http://www.crunchyroll.com/"&gt;Crunchyroll&lt;/a&gt; is simulcasting (streaming the episodes right after they air in Japan), one episode each week, and even with English and Portuguese subtitles! I find it incredible that it's possible to watch an anime that just aired in Japan, and that it has Portuguese subtitles no less, especially considering how Brazil tends to be behind when getting releases of anything (not limited to anime), when it gets the releases at all...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first P5 episode came out for free right on the day it aired in Japan. As for the second one, which aired today (the 14th), was released only for premium users for now, and the episode page says it'll be available for free on the 21st. Thus, we can conclude that the normal rule (free users must wait one week to get access to the episodes) is still valid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.crunchyroll.com/persona5-the-animation"&gt;Here's the link for watching the anime&lt;/a&gt;. There's no need to even register at the site. Just open each episode's page and watch... although, if you're watching the anime for free, be prepared to see a lot of ads and commercials. I'm not complaining, though. I'm just glad I can watch it at all, for free, and legally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Games</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/watch-the-p5-anime/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 22:06:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How Persona 5 Sparked My Interest in the World of Coffee</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/p5-coffee/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Let Me Explain!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not the first time that a game from the Persona series makes me go out of my way to learn something new. The game Persona 3 even made me &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/p3-food-ramen"&gt;try to prepare ramen&lt;/a&gt; even though cooking isn't my thing. Now, it's Persona 5's turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Persona 5, while acting just like a normal student during the day and fighting injustice and corrupt people at night, the young protagonist is forced to live in the attic in a coffee shop, and one of the activities to get items for missions is learning to prepare a good cup of coffee. But it isn't just any coffee!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, when the protagonist prepares coffee, the cafe owner comes and tastes the result, then says something like, "From this taste, you used beans 'XYZ,' didn't you? Let me explain!" and proceeds to release some trivia about the given coffee beans. In my case, it got to a point where he stopped coming to taste the coffee and give trivia, and I thought it wouldn't happen anymore. Also, he always said the coffee was bland, and I thought this was his only possible response. So, I thought, "If there's no more trivia and the coffee will be bland forever anyway, then why should I waste my time? The ingame days are limited, and there are more important things to do," and gave up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, later I found out I was totally mistaken, both about the trivia and the responses. I should've kept insisting. Apparently, I hadn't seen even the half of it! The user Chapsthedude on Reddit compiled &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Persona5/comments/7xulg3/let_me_explain_sojiros_coffee_and_curry_trivia/"&gt;all (or if not all, almost)&lt;/a&gt; coffee trivia, and there are even two Brazilian coffees, the Brazilian 2/18 (according to the game, it's also known as Santos, where 2 refers to the quality and 18 is the bean size) and the Brazilian Bourbon. I thought this was very cool!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A Few Discoveries&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've always enjoyed coffee, but had never gone beyond the common supermarket coffees or espressos from snack bars once in a while. Before Persona 5, I had no idea how the coffee world could be so vast. The game got me curious, and I decided to do some reading-up. Then, I learned that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm not sure if it's the same in English, but here in Brazil we classify coffee in three "levels:" traditional coffee - the mostly dark and bitter coffee of the common supermarket-variety -, superior coffee - has slightly better beans - and the specialty or gourmet coffee - contains the best of the best beans produced, and obviously are the most expensive (these are the most exported ones).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are two economically relevant coffee species: arabica coffee and robusta coffee. Arabica represents 3/4 of the coffee production worldwide, has a wide variety of beans and flavors, and less caffeine. As it's more delicate and difficult to grow and process, it's more expensive. Gourmet coffee is usually 100% Arabica. Robusta coffee is produced in less quantity but is cheaper, and is the one the general population usually consumes. It's said that robusta can produce drinks of quality as good as arabica with proper care in cultivation and processing, but this doesn't happen much yet, and robusta coffee usually ends up relegated to cheap and bitter supermarket coffee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are beans and beans with different characteristics and flavors (some are sweeter, others more citric), different levels of roast (light, medium, dark), different brewing methods (filter, French press, espresso, moka...) with appropriate grinding thicknesses for each one, among other things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The darker the roast, the more bitter the result, because roasting too much will burn all the sugars in the coffee, in the same way caramel (burnt sugar) is a bit bitter. And this is why the more common (and cheaper) supermarket coffees tend to be darker and more bitter. They may contain a mix of robusta and arabica with "defective" beans, the ones that aren't good enough for gourmet coffee standards, and over-roasted to disguise the imperfections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's best to drink freshly roasted and freshly ground coffee (preferably brewed soon after grinding). The more time passes after roasting and grinding, the more the coffee loses its aroma and taste.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you still don't have grinding equipment, you can go to a coffee shop and buy the recently roasted coffee beans they sell (they can grind the beans for you if you ask). It's not possible to brew the coffee right away (because it has to wait for you to at least get home first :P ), but it's a good choice for those who are starting out and don't have the equipment yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Testing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was curious to try some of these specialty coffees, but I didn't know any real coffee shops (apart from those neighborhood snack bars that serve espresso). So, to start, I decided to do a test with some ground gourmet coffees I found in the Pão de Açúcar mini market close to my home. They indeed taste different from what I was used to (don't be fooled. Even those light-colored coffees may have a strong flavor!). Overall, I liked it! The problem is that it's impossible to know when the beans were roasted and ground (as these products likely don't sell much because they are more expensive than the most common coffees, I don't doubt they've been sitting on the store's shelf for at least a month!). As it's kind of expensive (at least here, a pack of 250 grams of gourmet coffee is sold around $25.00 BRL - roughly $8 USD -, while a pack of 500 grams of "traditional" coffee is around $10.00 BRL, or around $3 USD), I just allowed myself the luxury of buy one 250 grams pack per month and drink it only on weekends. This increases the "time passed after roasting and grinding" factor even more, but oh well...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to go deeper into the coffee world, but I've been procrastinating it for at least half a year because of the risk of getting addicted, becoming too picky and getting unable to return to ordinary coffee, which means it can become quite expensive. I was considering to buy an entry-level manual grinder (about $200 BRL, around 70 USD) to be able to have freshly-ground coffee, and maybe some different coffee maker like an Aeropress (also around $200 BRL here), aside from the beans themselves ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still wasn't brave enough to take the plunge and buy equipment, as I still haven't tried coffee brewed using different methods, and don't have any reference of flavors or brewing methods to see what I like best. My coworker advised me to go to a Starbucks coffee shop, try their coffee of the day, and bring home the ground beans while I don't have a grinder. I searched for the nearest Starbucks, and found the one at the Metro Santa Cruz Shopping mall (São Paulo/SP, Brazil), and I decided that Id go there during my vacation. And I finally did!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan was to try the coffee of the day, and buy the beans of the same coffee to compare the flavor with the output of the simple coffee maker at home... but it didn't go the way I had expected. As it was the first time, I fumbled a little while placing the order, and the attendant was unable to explain how things worked. He only gave me the option to have espresso or coffee with milk (and it seems that they only had espresso machines), while the beans of the day's campaign were from a Papua New Guinea coffee. To me, the taste of the espresso was "just right" (unlike another store's espresso I had, which was very strong and left a not very pleasant sensation in my mouth). Then I found out that they also sell the beans they use for that espresso (it's their own blend they call Espresso Roast), but since I don't have an espresso machine, it wouldn't do. I ended up taking the New Guinea one anyway... at least I'm sure it's freshly roasted and ground!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is how the coffee looks like in the cup, after going through the simple coffee maker here... (own picture, taken with a cellphone)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="img-center" src="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/uploads/images/p5-coffee/png-coffee-cup.jpg" width="576" height="1024" alt="The Guinea coffee inside a cup which has the word 'confidence' written on it in Japanese, translated as 'confiança' in Portuguese"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the taste very smooth, but I'm not sure if I could identify the herbal touches mentioned in the package (there's a little flavor that reminds me of something but I don't know if that's what the package is talking about). I wonder if other cooking methods / equipment would make these flavors stand out a bit more. I also tried the coffee with milk and it was... interesting. It's as though I had mixed something salty together with something sweet to balance it out (though I didn't put sugar in either the coffee or the milk). Or at least, this was the impression I had. Sorry, I don't know how to describe it :P . This was the best I could do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to wrap this post up, here's the sound of the coffee being served! XD Not that it was necessary, but I just felt like recording it. At least, if I decide to do a Persona 5 audio drama that has a scene involving coffee, I already have the sound effect :P .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder="0" scrolling="no" src="https://freesound.org/embed/sound/iframe/421927/simple/medium/" width="481" height="86"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(* The boss suddenly appears*)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Ah. From this taste, you used the Guinea PNG beans, didn't you? Let me explain! The Papua New Guinea coffee, or PNG, is produced on Papua New Guinea Island, which is about 150km north of Australia. The coffee is produced in a hard-to-reach region, on soils rich with nutrients from volcanic activity. It produces a drink with a light flavor and herbal touches." A pause. "... But you still have a lot to learn. Your result is still bland... There's much room for improvement! Starting with the equipment..."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ugh... okay, I'll think about it. I don't know where I want to get with this yet, but I'll keep insisting. We'll see!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is more or less how I think the trivia about this coffee could be if it were in Persona 5. Mostly based on info written on the package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A Few Links About Coffee&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Persona5/comments/7xulg3/let_me_explain_sojiros_coffee_and_curry_trivia/"&gt;Reddit - Persona 5 coffee trivia compilation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.primermagazine.com/2015/learn/upgrade-your-joe-a-beginners-guide-to-better-coffee"&gt;Upgrade Your Joe: A Beginner’s Guide to Better Coffee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.thecoffeefaq.com/"&gt;The Coffee FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Games</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/p5-coffee/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 19:05:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Persona 5 Opening - UTAU Cover</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/p5-op-utau-cover/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I mentioned &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/getting-ready-for-persona5"&gt;how I was excited about the release of the game Persona 5&lt;/a&gt;. I had been so excited that I began writing fanfictions about it months before the game had even come out in Japan and we had nearly no information about the characters or the setting. On September 15, 2016, the game was released in Japan (I'm writing this on September 15, 2017. So, it was exactly one year ago! :D ). And on April 4, 2017, the western version finally came out (and even had a Japanese audio option as free DLC, like I had wanted).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually don't preorder games, but with Persona 5, I couldn't resist. I got it from an online games store from my country. I traded in two old GBA games I had lying around which I had barely touched (they came with the second-hand GBA I had bought at the end of 2008), and the store gave me an additional discount for paying in full (in the end, the total discount amounted to around R$91 BRL, roughly $30 USD). The store shipped the product quickly, and the game was in my hands on release day (April 7th here in Brazil, unlike North America and Europe that got it on April 4th).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn't say that the game has no flaws, but it was as great and fun as I had expected. I've already beaten it twice (with Japanese audio) and gotten the Platinum trophy in my second playthrough. I'm currently on my third playthrough (trying out the English audio). There are many small details that can easily go unnoticed in the first, or even the second playthrough. Persona 5 continues entertaining me even now, even though it's my third time going through it (and giving me even more fanfic ideas :P ). I'm very satisfied, and glad that it lived up to all the excitement I had since last year. The game is worth every cent, plus the work I went through to trade in the used GBA cartridges :D .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To celebrate platinuming the game, as well as finishing one of my &lt;a href="http://archiveofourown.org/works/7667629"&gt;long fanfictions&lt;/a&gt; (that I began writing before the games Japanese release last year), I did an UTAU cover of the game's opening song, "Wake Up, Get Up, Get Out There." UTAU? Yes, a singing sinthesis software. I've already talked about it &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/accessibility-and-how-i-began-using-vocaloid"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, where I had come to the conclusion that it was unusable without a mouse and I wouldn't be able to use it ever. I was wrong! I suddenly decided to tamper with the program again a few months back, and what was my surprise when I managed to connect a few syllables smoothly! So, I decided to do a cover, and here it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link to the video is below, featuring... the Brasilian version of the game's cover art! (there's stuff written in Portuguese, but the game is in English) ... And a (probably very inaccurate) instrumental made by me, using the accompaniment generator software &lt;a href="http://www.mellowood.ca/mma/"&gt;MMA (Musical MIDI Accompaniment)&lt;/a&gt; and my Motif XF keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credits and more details are in the video description, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ihhnxkKJ8e8"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get the audio only:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="https://od.lk/d/122177959_VkyiM/wake-up_0.1.ogg"&gt;wake-up_0.1.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.4shared.com/mp3/EqnHv6Yqca/wake-up_01.html"&gt;wake-up_0.1.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><category>UTAU</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/p5-op-utau-cover/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 21:16:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I got a New PS4 Slim! A Few Impressions and Quick Tips</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/ps4-slim-review/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main reason why I had never been interested in the PS3, and why it took me so long to get interested in the PS4 was because they had no games that appealed to me. The PS3 and the PS4's main strengths seem to be games for hardcore gamers, action-packed games with stunning graphics. Mainly shooting, war, and football games, which aren't my cup of tea (I prefer quieter games like turn-based RPGs). However, some JRPGs (Japanese RPGs) of my interest are coming to the PS4, especially Persona 5, RED ASH, and Final Fantasy VII Remake. So, I finally decided that I'd buy a PS4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After many months of waiting and comparing prices, and then learning that the PS4 Slim would be released, thus having to wait even longer, I finally got my PS4! (as the saying goes, good things come to those who wait :P ) Actually, I was going to wait a bit more, but the US elections results made the US Dollar rates against the Brazilian Real rise like crazy, and because games are mostly imported here in Brazil, prices only tend to go up. So, I decided it was now or... well, I wouldn't say, "never," but who knows when prices would return to acceptable values ​​if I were to wait more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I opted for the PS4 Slim because, according to my researches, it is quieter and consumes less power, and the battery of the (wireless) controller's new revision that comes with it also lasts longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips and observations that I gathered during my researches and tests, as well as my impressions on the console. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/ps4-slim-review/"&gt;more…&lt;/a&gt; (8 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Games</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/ps4-slim-review/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 23:55:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Watch the Persona 5 Special Anime Episode Online</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/watch-p5-db-online/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/getting-ready-for-persona5"&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about the Persona series, and how I'm excited about Persona 5's release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On September 3rd, 2016, a special Persona 5 anime episode aired in Japan to promote the game. It is titled, "Persona 5 the Animation - the Day Breakers," and is about the main gang doing a random sidequest (it's an optional mission that doesn't interfere with the main plot of the game. So, no worries about spoilers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.crunchyroll.com/"&gt;Crunchyroll&lt;/a&gt; is a site that licenses and legally streams anime with English subtitles. It shares the money earned from its subscribers with the anime creators, and has also a selection of anime available to watch for free (although with ads interrupting the video from time to time :P ). The site made the Persona 5 special episode available for its subscribers on September 3rd, simultaneously as the anime's airing in Japan. One week later (on September 10th), the episode also became available for non-subscribers, and can be watched for free &lt;a href="http://www.crunchyroll.com/persona5-the-animation-the-day-breakers-/episode-0-persona-5-the-animation-the-day-breakers-719079"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (no account or anything needed. Just enter the page and watch!).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Games</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/watch-p5-db-online/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:36:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Getting Ready for Persona 5</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/getting-ready-for-persona5/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year (2015) I cleared the game Persona 3 FES (for Playstation 2), and in the beginning of this year (2016) I beat Persona 4 (also for PS2). An extremely brief introduction for those who don't know about these games: the Persona games are JRPGs (japanese RPGs) about high school students that need to balance studies, outings with friends, and fights against supernatural phenomena where they summon a kind of "inner self" in the form of creatures called "Persona." Both the Personas and the enemies are based on mythological beings, angels, demons and such. The games contain charismatic and well-developed characters, engaging storylines, and humorous scenes typical of anime. From Persona 3 onwards, the games have a calendar system where we follow the protagonists during the course of one year, where we can observe several aspects of Japanese culture such as typical foods (these games even made me &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/p3-food-ramen"&gt;try my hand at preparing ramen&lt;/a&gt;! :P ), some locations, and even what days are holidays on Japan's calendar! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/getting-ready-for-persona5/"&gt;more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Games</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/getting-ready-for-persona5/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 17:25:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>In the Mood to DASH, Reloaded! (Updated 2015/08/04)</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-redash/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'd already &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-dash"&gt;talked here on the blog&lt;/a&gt; about my interest in the Rockman DASH series (known as Mega Man Legends in the West), which unfortunately had its third game canceled and left its fans craving for more. Capcom hasn't shown any interest in continuing the series, but a few days ago, a light at the end of the tunnel came from somewhere else. Comcept, the company founded by Keiji Inafune (Rockman / Mega Man series' creator, who had left Capcom) launched a project to create a series that will become the spiritual successor to DASH/Legends. The project is called "RED ASH." &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-redash/"&gt;more…&lt;/a&gt; (11 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Games</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-redash/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 18:12:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rockman DASH - "We are the Three Bonne Brothers" Violin Arrangements</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-2/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those who have read my &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/gossec-gavotte-fvl-cover"&gt;other&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/virtual-violins"&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt; probably noticed that I'm currently obsessed with violins. It turns out that I couldn't resist and, in march of 2015, I began taking lessons to learn to play the real thing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three months have passed, and I continue my &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-1"&gt;arrangements of the song "We Are the Three Bonne Brothers"&lt;/a&gt; from Rockman DASH/Mega Man Legends. Today I bring a few more versions, this time with violins, both the virtual one and the real one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These where made for my fan fiction, "&lt;a href="https://www.fanfiction.net/s/10564022/1/Trigger-of-Change"&gt;Trigger of Change&lt;/a&gt;," where the Servbots learn to play the violin. The piano is the same as the &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-1"&gt;"Marimbonnes" version&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the virtual one, made with the Embertone Friedlander Violin VST.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/101759890_xIo2h_d1b5/bonnes-fvl01.ogg"&gt;bonnes-fvl01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/wxHz8p3Qba/bonnes-fvl01.html"&gt;bonnes-fvl01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is my attempt at playing it with a real violin. Warning: beginner level playing (just three months of taking weekly lessons), and the intonation is still quite off. Also, it's my first time trying to record an acoustic instrument (recorded with a Zoom H4n portable recorder).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/101759900_0s6x3_4a1d/bonnes-realviolin01.ogg"&gt;bonnes-realviolin01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/MJN7Xw8xce/bonnes-realviolin01.html"&gt;bonnes-realviolin01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three violins version: until I arrived at the final result above, I had to record the song over twenty times! I didn't want so many takes to go to waste, so I selected the better three of my recording (mis)takes and glued them together. The result is a trio of clumsy and out of tune Servbots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/101759905_WOe2Z_98a6/bonnes-threeviolins01.ogg"&gt;bonnes-threeviolins01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/4mLQhgynba/bonnes-threeviolins01.html"&gt;bonnes-threeviolins01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three violins + Friedlander Violin version: the "trio" above playing along with the virtual one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/101759911_UKCuo_6679/bonnes-threeviolins-and-fvl01.ogg"&gt;bonnes-threeviolins-and-fvl01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/FPJoQfbgba/bonnes-threeviolins-and-fvl01.html"&gt;bonnes-threeviolins-and-fvl01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><category>Violin</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-2/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 21:35:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rockman DASH - "We are the Three Bonne Brothers" Keyboard Arrangements</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-1/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are my keyboard arrangements of the song "We are the Three Bonne Brothers", also known as the theme song for the Bonnes, the charismatic air pirates from the Rockman DASH/Mega Man Legends series. Performed and recorded on a Yamaha Motif XF keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piano and flute version (shorter): &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/99499160_o5e2n_d694/bonne-brothers01.ogg"&gt;bonne-brothers01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/e5QxhGKVce/bonne-brothers01.html"&gt;bonne-brothers01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piano and flute version (longer): &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/99826482_d2ohR_366c/bonne-brothers02.ogg"&gt;bonne-brothers02.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/E2BgnW5Wba/bonne-brothers02.html"&gt;bonne-brothers02.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update (2015/04/17): piano and marimba version: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/99952953_GaPC6_61a8/marimbonnes01.ogg"&gt;marimbonnes01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/1I8IVJhPce/marimbonnes01.html"&gt;marimbonnes01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-1/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 12:33:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>In the Mood to DASH!</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-dash/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I began revisiting the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mega_Man_Legends"&gt;Rockman DASH (Mega Man Legends)&lt;/a&gt; series, watching (read "listening") some playthroughs and cutscenes to refresh my memory (I don't have the games anymore), trying to finally understand the plot. I didn't know enough of either Japanese or English to be able to grasp it at the time I played, which was some 12 years ago. Turns out that I can't fully figure it out even now :P. I have the impression that the second game (the one with the major plot points) felt a bit rushed, some important things are mentioned only in passing and aren't expanded anywhere. After the cancellation of DASH/Legends 3, it's unlikely that we'll be seeing these answers anytime soon. I also noticed differences between the dialogue from the English version and the original Japanese (inconsistencies in the translation/usage of names and terms) which may affect how we view a characters personality, as well as parts of the plot itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from that, I still think it's a good plot, albeit a bit confusing and full of unexplored potential. That calls to one thing: fan fiction!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After checking the playthroughs, then reading a few discussions and fan fictions to see how other people interpret the plot, I was inspired to write my own fanfic, intitled "&lt;a href="https://www.fanfiction.net/s/10564022/1/Trigger-of-Change"&gt;Trigger of Change&lt;/a&gt;". And like I did with my &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/pokemon/sl/drama"&gt;Pokemon fic&lt;/a&gt;, I began making Japanese anime style audio dramas out of it. This prompted the creation of a new &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/rockman"&gt;Rockman section&lt;/a&gt; on the site, with the page for the audio dramas &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/rockman/toc/drama"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude this post, I leave you with my VOCALOID cover of "Anata no Kaze ga Fuku Kara", the ending song to the first game. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/89882897_wjfA3_acdc/gumi_power_-_dash-kaze_0.1.ogg"&gt;OGG (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/44Pq_-xLba/gumi_power_-_dash-kaze_01.html"&gt;MP3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zW77ScDa3hA"&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aiyumi, DASHing off!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><category>Site Updates</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-dash/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 18:51:45 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>