<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Aiyumi.Github.Io (Posts about Games)</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/tag/games.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 Aiyumi &lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/"&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:37:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Watch the Persona 5 Anime Online and for Free</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/watch-the-p5-anime/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game Persona 5 which I've been talking about so much got an anime adaptation! It's called "Persona 5 the Animation" and began airing in Japan on April 7th, 2018. And just like what happened to the &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/watch-p5-db-online"&gt;Day Breakers special episode&lt;/a&gt;, the streaming site &lt;a href="http://www.crunchyroll.com/"&gt;Crunchyroll&lt;/a&gt; is simulcasting (streaming the episodes right after they air in Japan), one episode each week, and even with English and Portuguese subtitles! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/watch-the-p5-anime/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Games</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/watch-the-p5-anime/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 22:06:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How Persona 5 Sparked My Interest in the World of Coffee</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/p5-coffee/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Let Me Explain!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not the first time that a game from the Persona series makes me go out of my way to learn something new. The game Persona 3 even made me &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/p3-food-ramen"&gt;try to prepare ramen&lt;/a&gt; even though cooking isn't my thing. Now, it's Persona 5's turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Persona 5, while acting just like a normal student during the day and fighting injustice and corrupt people at night, the young protagonist is forced to live in the attic in a coffee shop, and one of the activities to get items for missions is learning to prepare a good cup of coffee. But it isn't just any coffee! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/p5-coffee/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (8 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Games</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/p5-coffee/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 19:05:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Persona 5 Opening - UTAU Cover</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/p5-op-utau-cover/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I mentioned &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/getting-ready-for-persona5"&gt;how I was excited about the release of the game Persona 5&lt;/a&gt;. I had been so excited that I began writing fanfictions about it months before the game had even come out in Japan and we had nearly no information about the characters or the setting. On September 15, 2016, the game was released in Japan (I'm writing this on September 15, 2017. So, it was exactly one year ago! :D ). And on April 4, 2017, the western version finally came out (and even had a Japanese audio option as free DLC, like I had wanted).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually don't preorder games, but with Persona 5, I couldn't resist. I got it from an online games store from my country. I traded in two old GBA games I had lying around which I had barely touched (they came with the second-hand GBA I had bought at the end of 2008), and the store gave me an additional discount for paying in full (in the end, the total discount amounted to around R$91 BRL, roughly $30 USD). The store shipped the product quickly, and the game was in my hands on release day (April 7th here in Brazil, unlike North America and Europe that got it on April 4th).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn't say that the game has no flaws, but it was as great and fun as I had expected. I've already beaten it twice (with Japanese audio) and gotten the Platinum trophy in my second playthrough. I'm currently on my third playthrough (trying out the English audio). There are many small details that can easily go unnoticed in the first, or even the second playthrough. Persona 5 continues entertaining me even now, even though it's my third time going through it (and giving me even more fanfic ideas :P ). I'm very satisfied, and glad that it lived up to all the excitement I had since last year. The game is worth every cent, plus the work I went through to trade in the used GBA cartridges :D .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To celebrate platinuming the game, as well as finishing one of my &lt;a href="http://archiveofourown.org/works/7667629"&gt;long fanfictions&lt;/a&gt; (that I began writing before the games Japanese release last year), I did an UTAU cover of the game's opening song, "Wake Up, Get Up, Get Out There." UTAU? Yes, a singing sinthesis software. I've already talked about it &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/accessibility-and-how-i-began-using-vocaloid"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, where I had come to the conclusion that it was unusable without a mouse and I wouldn't be able to use it ever. I was wrong! I suddenly decided to tamper with the program again a few months back, and what was my surprise when I managed to connect a few syllables smoothly! So, I decided to do a cover, and here it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link to the video is below, featuring... the Brasilian version of the game's cover art! (there's stuff written in Portuguese, but the game is in English) ... And a (probably very inaccurate) instrumental made by me, using the accompaniment generator software &lt;a href="http://www.mellowood.ca/mma/"&gt;MMA (Musical MIDI Accompaniment)&lt;/a&gt; and my Motif XF keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credits and more details are in the video description, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ihhnxkKJ8e8"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get the audio only:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="https://od.lk/d/122177959_VkyiM/wake-up_0.1.ogg"&gt;wake-up_0.1.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.4shared.com/mp3/EqnHv6Yqca/wake-up_01.html"&gt;wake-up_0.1.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><category>UTAU</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/p5-op-utau-cover/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 21:16:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I got a New PS4 Slim! A Few Impressions and Quick Tips</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/ps4-slim-review/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main reason why I had never been interested in the PS3, and why it took me so long to get interested in the PS4 was because they had no games that appealed to me. The PS3 and the PS4's main strengths seem to be games for hardcore gamers, action-packed games with stunning graphics. Mainly shooting, war, and football games, which aren't my cup of tea (I prefer quieter games like turn-based RPGs). However, some JRPGs (Japanese RPGs) of my interest are coming to the PS4, especially Persona 5, RED ASH, and Final Fantasy VII Remake. So, I finally decided that I'd buy a PS4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After many months of waiting and comparing prices, and then learning that the PS4 Slim would be released, thus having to wait even longer, I finally got my PS4! (as the saying goes, good things come to those who wait :P ) Actually, I was going to wait a bit more, but the US elections results made the US Dollar rates against the Brazilian Real rise like crazy, and because games are mostly imported here in Brazil, prices only tend to go up. So, I decided it was now or... well, I wouldn't say, "never," but who knows when prices would return to acceptable values ​​if I were to wait more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I opted for the PS4 Slim because, according to my researches, it is quieter and consumes less power, and the battery of the (wireless) controller's new revision that comes with it also lasts longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips and observations that I gathered during my researches and tests, as well as my impressions on the console. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/ps4-slim-review/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (8 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Games</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/ps4-slim-review/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 23:55:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Watch the Persona 5 Special Anime Episode Online</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/watch-p5-db-online/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/getting-ready-for-persona5"&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about the Persona series, and how I'm excited about Persona 5's release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On September 3rd, 2016, a special Persona 5 anime episode aired in Japan to promote the game. It is titled, "Persona 5 the Animation - the Day Breakers," and is about the main gang doing a random sidequest (it's an optional mission that doesn't interfere with the main plot of the game. So, no worries about spoilers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.crunchyroll.com/"&gt;Crunchyroll&lt;/a&gt; is a site that licenses and legally streams anime with English subtitles. It shares the money earned from its subscribers with the anime creators, and has also a selection of anime available to watch for free (although with ads interrupting the video from time to time :P ). The site made the Persona 5 special episode available for its subscribers on September 3rd, simultaneously as the anime's airing in Japan. One week later (on September 10th), the episode also became available for non-subscribers, and can be watched for free &lt;a href="http://www.crunchyroll.com/persona5-the-animation-the-day-breakers-/episode-0-persona-5-the-animation-the-day-breakers-719079"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (no account or anything needed. Just enter the page and watch!).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Games</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/watch-p5-db-online/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:36:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Getting Ready for Persona 5</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/getting-ready-for-persona5/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year (2015) I cleared the game Persona 3 FES (for Playstation 2), and in the beginning of this year (2016) I beat Persona 4 (also for PS2). An extremely brief introduction for those who don't know about these games: the Persona games are JRPGs (japanese RPGs) about high school students that need to balance studies, outings with friends, and fights against supernatural phenomena where they summon a kind of "inner self" in the form of creatures called "Persona." Both the Personas and the enemies are based on mythological beings, angels, demons and such. The games contain charismatic and well-developed characters, engaging storylines, and humorous scenes typical of anime. From Persona 3 onwards, the games have a calendar system where we follow the protagonists during the course of one year, where we can observe several aspects of Japanese culture such as typical foods (these games even made me &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/p3-food-ramen"&gt;try my hand at preparing ramen&lt;/a&gt;! :P ), some locations, and even what days are holidays on Japan's calendar! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/getting-ready-for-persona5/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Games</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/getting-ready-for-persona5/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 17:25:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>In the Mood to DASH, Reloaded! (Updated 2015/08/04)</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-redash/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'd already &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-dash"&gt;talked here on the blog&lt;/a&gt; about my interest in the Rockman DASH series (known as Mega Man Legends in the West), which unfortunately had its third game canceled and left its fans craving for more. Capcom hasn't shown any interest in continuing the series, but a few days ago, a light at the end of the tunnel came from somewhere else. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-redash/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (11 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Games</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-redash/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 18:12:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rockman DASH - "We are the Three Bonne Brothers" Violin Arrangements</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-2/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those who have read my &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/gossec-gavotte-fvl-cover"&gt;other&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/virtual-violins"&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt; probably noticed that I'm currently obsessed with violins. It turns out that I couldn't resist and, in march of 2015, I began taking lessons to learn to play the real thing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three months have passed, and I continue my &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-1"&gt;arrangements of the song "We Are the Three Bonne Brothers"&lt;/a&gt; from Rockman DASH/Mega Man Legends. Today I bring a few more versions, this time with violins, both the virtual one and the real one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These where made for my fan fiction, "&lt;a href="https://www.fanfiction.net/s/10564022/1/Trigger-of-Change"&gt;Trigger of Change&lt;/a&gt;," where the Servbots learn to play the violin. The piano is the same as the &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-1"&gt;"Marimbonnes" version&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the virtual one, made with the Embertone Friedlander Violin VST.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/101759890_xIo2h_d1b5/bonnes-fvl01.ogg"&gt;bonnes-fvl01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/wxHz8p3Qba/bonnes-fvl01.html"&gt;bonnes-fvl01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is my attempt at playing it with a real violin. Warning: beginner level playing (just three months of taking weekly lessons), and the intonation is still quite off. Also, it's my first time trying to record an acoustic instrument (recorded with a Zoom H4n portable recorder).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/101759900_0s6x3_4a1d/bonnes-realviolin01.ogg"&gt;bonnes-realviolin01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/MJN7Xw8xce/bonnes-realviolin01.html"&gt;bonnes-realviolin01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three violins version: until I arrived at the final result above, I had to record the song over twenty times! I didn't want so many takes to go to waste, so I selected the better three of my recording (mis)takes and glued them together. The result is a trio of clumsy and out of tune Servbots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/101759905_WOe2Z_98a6/bonnes-threeviolins01.ogg"&gt;bonnes-threeviolins01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/4mLQhgynba/bonnes-threeviolins01.html"&gt;bonnes-threeviolins01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three violins + Friedlander Violin version: the "trio" above playing along with the virtual one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/101759911_UKCuo_6679/bonnes-threeviolins-and-fvl01.ogg"&gt;bonnes-threeviolins-and-fvl01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/FPJoQfbgba/bonnes-threeviolins-and-fvl01.html"&gt;bonnes-threeviolins-and-fvl01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><category>Violin</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-2/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 21:35:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rockman DASH - "We are the Three Bonne Brothers" Keyboard Arrangements</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-1/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are my keyboard arrangements of the song "We are the Three Bonne Brothers", also known as the theme song for the Bonnes, the charismatic air pirates from the Rockman DASH/Mega Man Legends series. Performed and recorded on a Yamaha Motif XF keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piano and flute version (shorter): &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/99499160_o5e2n_d694/bonne-brothers01.ogg"&gt;bonne-brothers01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/e5QxhGKVce/bonne-brothers01.html"&gt;bonne-brothers01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piano and flute version (longer): &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/99826482_d2ohR_366c/bonne-brothers02.ogg"&gt;bonne-brothers02.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/E2BgnW5Wba/bonne-brothers02.html"&gt;bonne-brothers02.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update (2015/04/17): piano and marimba version: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/99952953_GaPC6_61a8/marimbonnes01.ogg"&gt;marimbonnes01.ogg (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/1I8IVJhPce/marimbonnes01.html"&gt;marimbonnes01.mp3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/bonnes-theme-arrange-1/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 12:33:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>In the Mood to DASH!</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-dash/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I began revisiting the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mega_Man_Legends"&gt;Rockman DASH (Mega Man Legends)&lt;/a&gt; series, watching (read "listening") some playthroughs and cutscenes to refresh my memory (I don't have the games anymore), trying to finally understand the plot. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-dash/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><category>Site Updates</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-dash/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 18:51:45 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>