<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aiyumi.Warpstar.Net (Posts about Site Updates)</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/tag/site-updates.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:46:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Status Update 2019/07/21</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/status-update-2019-07-21/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot has already happened in this year of 2019:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year's first half was particularly hard. My mother got sick, and we went through some tough times. For a few months, I had no time nor inspiration and wasn't in the mood to post anything anywhere, and sadly had to put my violin lessons on hold as well. I eventually managed to &lt;a href="https://steemit.com/life/@aiyumi/after-a-storm-comes-a-little-party"&gt;post a summary of the story on Steemit&lt;/a&gt; and also tell my fan fictions' readers the reason of my lack of updates (we got touched at how supportive some of the readers were). My mother's treatment is ongoing and will only end at the end of the year. The worst is thankfully over and she's getting better. But it was only last month that things began resembling normalcy, and I fully recovered my mood to get back into the games, posts and fan fictions mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On to the more positive news: while my mother was unable to do the household chores, I ended up cooking a lot, and got many tips from my aunt that had come from another city to help us out. My cooking skills have improved significantly. I used &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/two-new-toys-in-the-kitchen"&gt;the air fryer and the electric pressure cooker&lt;/a&gt; many times, and surprisingly without much impact on the electricity bill. Even &lt;a href="https://steemit.com/life/@aiyumi/after-a-storm-comes-a-little-party"&gt;my mother's birthday cake&lt;/a&gt; was made in the electric pressure cooker! At least my cooking resolutions for this year, which I had mentioned in the electric appliances post&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May 2019 be a year when many tasty foods come out of my electric pans!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;are coming true! Now I'm reducing my carbohydrate intake, and learning some cool recipes too, like &lt;a href="https://steemit.com/qurator/@aiyumi/low-carb-gluten-free-meat-croquettes"&gt;these croquettes without flour nor breadcrumbs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I helped complete the Portuguese translation of the &lt;a href="http://slackware.uk/slint/x86_64/slint-14.2.1/"&gt;Slint 14.2.1.2&lt;/a&gt; installer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Slint, a Slackware (and Slint) compatible version of the Voxin text to speech software was released, and I can finally read and write in Japanese on the computer again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had wanted to change this blog's layout, as the one it uses is there since 2011! I had tought of fiddling with this during my vacation, but the vacation was during the year's difficult moments, and I didn't even touch the layout. It's old, outdated, not modern at all and is not responsive (doesn't adapt to different devices like tablets and smartphones). While some people told me they like the layout and said the text is easy to read, others bashed it and said the text is unreadable and only visually impaired visitors with screen readers would be able to understand what's on the site! (those were commenters from BR-Linux. I wonder whether they were on mobile)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have the disposition and patience to try to design site templates like I had in the beginning, and am thinking of just slapping the blog with Nikola (the blog engine I use)'s default theme, as anything must be better than this old thing! Or if anyone has any suggestion for a good template, preferably lightweight and that doesn't rely too much (or at all) on JavaScript (even if it's a Wordpress theme or something. I'm willing to port it), please &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/contact"&gt;tell me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was about all I wanted to say. Sorry for the lack of posts in this blog, and if you would like to read more posts from me, you can find more on &lt;a href="https://steemit.com/pt/@aiyumi"&gt;Steemit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/status-update-2019-07-21/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 23:43:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Two New Toys in the Kitchen</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/two-new-toys-in-the-kitchen/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/p3-food-ramen"&gt;post about ramen&lt;/a&gt;, I had talked about some of the obstacles I face in the kitchen, and that cooking isn't my cup of tea. But as evidenced by that post itself, sometimes crazy things happen when I decide to make something different...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My biggest problem is still my insecurity when dealing with the stove. But then, it occurred to me that I had no problem operating the coffee maker and the rice cooker, two electric appliances. So, I decided to research about other kinds of electric pans to see if they could be something for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of October, I began looking into electric pans, features, advantages (easy control of cooking times, better preservation of food nutrients, safety mechanisms to avoid accidents, the convenience I'm used to from the rice cooker...), disadvantages (the only disadvantage I found is that using these machines will obviously have an impact on the electricity bills, but I hope we can balance their use so that the impact isn't too bad). I wrote a more detailed post about my findings on Steemit. You may read it &lt;a href="https://steemit.com/kitchen/@aiyumi/running-away-from-the-stove-looking-into-electric-pans-and-such"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November, I managed to buy an air fryer and an electric pressure cooker on Black Friday, and here we are in December! I'm still learning how to use my two new toys, still relying on sighted help until I get the hang of it, but am confident that soon I'll be able to operate the appliances with no problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first experiments didn't come out perfect, but thankfully all of them were edible (and not just once :P )! So, I believe it's a good start!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote about my mistakes and successes so far (mostly mistakes :P ) as well as other considerations about the pans, and you may read about them &lt;a href="https://steemit.com/kitchen/@aiyumi/kitchen-beginner-adventures-testing-my-new-electric-pans"&gt;in this other post on Steemit&lt;/a&gt;. Interestingly, "I'll get this right &lt;strong&gt;next time&lt;/strong&gt;!" became a recurring sentence in my head. And for someone that's not much into cooking, being this motivated to persist and improve can only be a good thing, no matter how I look at it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, to many "next times," and nice amounts of progress next year! May 2019 be a year when many tasty foods come out of my electric pans! XD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: the electricity bill for most of November + beginning of December has arrived. It's the one with the results of all my uses of the two pans so far (the four experiments described in the second link's post). Everything normal for now. At least this time, the impact isn't even noticeable, but since I've used the pans just a few times so far, it's still early to celebrate. I'll continue using them carefully and monitoring the bills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/two-new-toys-in-the-kitchen/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 23:42:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Small Status Update and a Post About Accessibility of Clickable HTML Elements</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/status-update-2018-07-20/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just passing by to show I'm still around :P . It's been a few months since I last posted anything here, but I still update my fan fiction every month. To my surprise, I've also been managing to be active on Steemit, posting at least once a week (twice if we consider I usually publish the same post both in Portuguese and in English). Incidentally, my last Steemit post was about the accessibility problems that happen a lot with clickable HTML objects, which may be of interest to anyone visiting my blog to read about accessibility. Below is the link to the post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://steemit.com/accessibility/@aiyumi/web-accessibility-clickable-objects-and-screen-readers"&gt;Web Accessibility - Clickable Objects and Screen Readers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find other posts on &lt;a href="https://steemit.com/@aiyumi"&gt;my Steemit blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/status-update-2018-07-20/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 17:35:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>My First Week on Steemit, and My First Impressions</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/steemit-first-impressions/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've never had much patience, nor luck, with social networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've tried to use twitter, but nothing came out of it. I didn't have the patience to read others' things and post constantly, and it was cumbersome to rephrase everything I wrote to fit the character limit. In the end, &lt;a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/aiyumi_en"&gt;my Twitter&lt;/a&gt; was relegated to just informing people about blog and fanfic updates. I only have like 7 followers, and my tweets don't even show on searches, just because they contain links (to this blog or to my fan fictions). From what I understood, the fact that they contain links and have no retweets makes the Twitter search engine bots think my tweets are spam! So, no one outside of my 7 followers can even find my tweets...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't have Facebook because I don't like it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updates to &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/AiyumiBr"&gt;my Youtube&lt;/a&gt; are few and far between because my visual impairment makes it hard for me to create visual content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm not on Deviantart because of the same reason above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since I've found a few interesting blogs on Tumblr, I once tried to use it, but gave up because the interface is completely unusable with screen reader software, thus inaccessible to visually impaired users who depend on screen readers to use the computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also, I'm more a reader than a poster (people who have seen this blog knows how infrequent my posts are). There's a community on Reddit, &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Persona5"&gt;r/Persona5&lt;/a&gt;, which I've been following since 2016, before the Persona 5 game came out in Japan. But I don't even have a Reddit account, and just read what other people post. Surprisingly, I have enough patience for that, as said community tends to have insightful discussions about the plot, the characters, and the game in general. But so far, nothing gave me enough incentive to actually go out of my way to create a Reddit account and go write something there, and I've been content just by reading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;And Now, There's Steemit...&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, one of my fanfic's readers, a talented artist that goes by the nickname &lt;a href="https://ayza-chan.deviantart.com/"&gt;Ayza&lt;/a&gt;, commented on my fanfic. I made a deal with her to request some artwork related to my fanfic, and she sent me links to the social networks where I could find her. Among these links was her profile page for a social network I had never heard before, called Steemit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around since 2016 and still in beta, &lt;a href="https://steemit.com/"&gt;Steemit&lt;/a&gt; is basically a social network that rewards people for posting content. Users that read and enjoy a post can upvote it (similar to the "likes" on Facebook or the "upvotes" on Reddit), comment on it (it's also possible to upvote comments), and repost it so that their followers see it, which gives more visibility to the post. One week after posting, the post's author earns some "points," which are actually cryptocurrencies (similar to the well-known Bitcoin) that can be used as power to make their votes be worth more "points" inside Steemit, or converted into normal money at a few cryptocurrency exchanges. This is an oversimplified explanation, and there's much more to Steemit, but this is the basic idea. The actual details are in the &lt;a href="https://steemit.com/faq.html"&gt;Steemit FAQ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the concepts interesting. The posts I came across were of good quality, and had nice and insightful comments. Steemit seemed to be a welcoming place, and did something most social networks didn't. It made me want to sign up! :P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I signed up. The only things they ask are an username, an e-mail address, and a cellphone number (to get a text message with a code for account validation). As with most sites that are in beta, there's a wait list. While I waited for my account to be approved, I read a few posts to learn more about how things on Steemit work. Four days later, my account was approved. Although it's not mandatory, it's customary for new users to make a self-introduction post using the "&lt;a href="https://steemit.com/trending/introduceyourself"&gt;introduceyourself&lt;/a&gt;" tag, and try to start engaging with the community. I &lt;a href="https://steemit.com/introduceyourself/@aiyumi/hello-from-brazil-ayza-introduced-me"&gt;made one&lt;/a&gt;, and surprisingly, some users took the time to welcome me and give me some tips on how to use the platform. Then, I learned that there's a growing community of Brazilian people, and which is quite friendly and helpful to newbies like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've come across a lot of well-written and interesting posts. I also learned about the existence of a video streaming site similar to Youtube called &lt;a href="https://d.tube/"&gt;DTube&lt;/a&gt; and an audio streaming site similar to Soundcloud called &lt;a href="https://dsound.audio/"&gt;DSound&lt;/a&gt; that use the same rewards system as Steemit. Since I have problems to find images to use as background for my occasional game music covers to post on Youtube, and Soundcloud is another site that failed to convince me to sign up, DSound might be a good option for me (it has no sign up and uses the Steemit account for login). However, DSound still has some accessibility problems - basically, the buttons don't have any text saying what they do (their functionality is represented by icons only) and visually impaired users who depend on screen readers can't know what the buttons are for -, but it's a young project with a lot of potential, and I hope it'll improve in this regard in the future. You can read the &lt;a href="https://steemit.com/video/@heimindanger/introducing-dtube-a-decentralized-video-platform-using-steem-and-ipfs"&gt;post explaining how DTube works here&lt;/a&gt;, and the one explaining DSound &lt;a href="https://steemit.com/music/@prc/introducing-dsound-a-decentralized-sound-platform-using-steem-and-ipfs"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The posts are a bit old and many things improved in both projects, but the basic idea about how they work remain the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of accessibility, Steemit itself is rather accessible, and my screen reader got along with it rather well. I've run into a few small problems, but nothing that really hinders my use of the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course not all is roses on Steemit. Not every post has good quality. There is crappy content, there's people that abuse the system with spam (this is inevitable everywhere, especially when rewards with monetary value are involved), and the platform still lacks some features that would provide a better user experience. Steemit is still in beta, far from perfect, and may be complicated to learn in the beginning. But one thing that made me identify with Steemit is that the community is very helpful and writes various posts to guide new users, or to recommend ways and tools to work around the platform's shortcomings. There are various recommendations of helpful posts by users on &lt;a href="https://steemit.com/welcome"&gt;Steemit's welcome page&lt;/a&gt;. Inspired by this, I also tried to do my part by writing a post about &lt;a href="https://steemit.com/steemit/@aiyumi/steemit-filtering-posts-by-authors-and-tags"&gt;filtering posts by authors and tags&lt;/a&gt; (hopefully it'll be of use to someone).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I'm enjoying the stay. One week in, and I got 14 followers. From their posts, I think three of them or so might be bots, but the others are real people (most of them are the ones who welcomed me in my introductory post) and are quite active in the Brazilian community. Avid social network users may laugh at this, but 14, or even 11 followers is a huge achievement to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will I make money on Steemit? Honestly, considering my lack of patience with social networks and my lack of ability to promote content, I doubt it. But I'm enjoying the content, and for now, I only wish I could get a bit more STEEM POWER so that my votes would be worth more and help give more visibility to the content I like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will I have enough patience to continue frequenting Steemit? This, only time will tell, but I hope so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A link to my Steemit profile is already on the sidebar, and is also below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://steemit.com/@aiyumi"&gt;https://steemit.com/@aiyumi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as I'd like to repost some things from this blog on there, I can't post the whole text because that would cause search engines to penalize either this blog or my Steemit blog for duplicate content. So, I'll do some experiments, alternate between posting here and linking from there, and vice versa. Let's see what happens...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit (13:35): wow, looks like Steemit brought in a few Twitter followers as well! The number went from 7 to 11 (11 here too? XD ) I only noticed this when I went to Twitter to publish a link to this blog post. :D&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/steemit-first-impressions/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 13:47:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Year, New Disk</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/new-year-new-disk/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018 arrived, and I kicked off the year with... a hard drive failure in my main PC. In the morning of January 4th, I had just started doing some job-related stuff (I'm working at home) when, suddenly, without any symptom or prior warning, the computer began emitting clicks, everything crashed, the machine stopped responding, and the only way to turn it off was by holding the power button for a few seconds. When I turned it back on, I got a hard disk failure message. I used a Linux live USB to try to see what was going on, and everything worked fine except for the HD. The disk wasn't even recognized, and kept emitting clicks. We opened the machine and replaced the SATA cables, but nothing changed (the cables weren't the problem). Conclusion: the HD died for good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Assessing the Losses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually make a backup once every week. Emphasis on "usually." Ironically, I hadn't made a backup the previous week, and thanks to this, I lost two weeks worth of changes (the previous week + the ongoing week when the HD died). Thankfully, I didn't lose progress on most of my work-related scripts because I had uploaded them to the office's servers. But I lost a whole chapter of one of the fanfics I'm writing which had taken me my free time of those last two weeks to put together, and I'm still trying to recover the motivation to write all of that again. I also lost the Windows partition, which I actually never bothered to back up thinking nothing important was inside... until, after I lost the drive, I remembered all my VOCALOID and UTAU project files were in there, including the USTs for the "&lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/p5-op-utau-cover"&gt;Wake Up, Get Up, Get Out There&lt;/a&gt;" UTAU cover that took me a month to finish. I had copied the generated audio files to my Linux partition, but not the USTs... :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Choosing a New Drive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After much consideration, I decided to get an SSD instead of another HD. SSD ("Solid State Drive") is a different kind of disk that has its memory on a chip (like the memory in SD cards or USB sticks), data is accessed straight from the chip and the disk doesn't need to spin like the HDs do, which makes it faster (I had heard the operating system boots up in a matter of seconds once the machine is turned on, and heavy programs open quickly). It's more durable, quieter and consumes less power than HDs. I've heard that after living with an SSD, it's hard to go back to the traditional HDs. I had been curious about SSDs for a few months, and decided I might as well turn the lemons into lemonade, take this "opportunity" to try it out and see what all the fuzz was about. The problem is that this technology is still a bit expensive, and I paid $375 BRL (roughly $120 USD) on an SSD that only has 240GB, and for that price I could have bought a normal 1TB HD... but it's fine. It may seem like too little space, but my old HD was 1TB and never came close to filling (at most it used 30GB from the root partition with Slackware Linux, 70GB from the separate home partition, and 50GB from the Windows partition, totaling around 150GB), so, I believe 240GB should be enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ordered a Western Digital SSD (WD Green 240GB) through Mercado Livre (a Latin-American online marketplace like Ebay). I bought it on Thursday night, it shipped on Friday morning, and arrived on Monday (I believe local postal services here don't work on weekends). While I waited for the SSD to arrive, I had to work using my netbook (a weaker machine where each page in Firefox takes like 20 seconds to load and Orca takes some more time to start reading it), and also where I downloaded the Linux ISOs to install once the SSD arrived. Then I connected an external DVD drive to the netbook, burned the ISO to a DVD RW, and that was it. Preparing the Linux ISOs was easy-peasy. On the other hand...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Trying to Download Windows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main operating system is Linux. The few Windows programs I sometimes use (mainly VOCALOID and UTAU) can run on Wine, but the problem is that Wine isn't accessible to visually impaired users because it doesn't implement accessibility interfaces, and no screen readers are able to run on it. But since Windows 7 came with my machine and I have the license, I decided I might as well use it. I had backed up Windows &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/adventures-with-a-new-computer"&gt;as soon as I bought the computer&lt;/a&gt; and had used up all my DVD RWs plus two more DVD Rs because I didn't have enough RWs. But that was a backup of a newly installed Windows with no security updates or anything, and worse, the backup could only be restored from inside a running Windows! Conclusion: that backup was as good as nothing. I'd have to reinstall everything from scratch. The problem is that Dell doesn't provide a Windows installation media, and the installer is located (guess where...) in a partition in the HD! Of course, the HD died, so the installer went down with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that there is a &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/software-download/windows7"&gt;Microsoft page where it should be possible to download the installer&lt;/a&gt;. Theoretically, I'd just need to enter my Windows serial code. It's what I did. However, the page returned an error saying that this code wouldn't do because it is from a version of Windows supplied by a computer manufacturer, and that I should contact the manufacturer (Dell in my case) to get their custom image (the version that comes with Dell utilities which I was unable to uninstall, and a lot of other crap that only wastes resources and disk space).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Dell page, I'd have to enter the "service tag" that's glued to the computer case, so that it displays content and downloads related to the product I purchased from them (my computer). I informed the code, but the downloads area for my machine's model only has drivers and nothing else. I browsed the help topics, and found out that there are three ways to get an installation media:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way they recommend is to use a program to generate and download a custom image. Of course, the program only runs on Windows (so, it's useless to me because I'm without Windows. No idea whether it'd run on Wine). I wanted to know if there was another way and, after much searching, I found the second way below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a &lt;a href="http://www.dell.com/support/home/drivers/osiso/win"&gt;page to download the Windows installation media&lt;/a&gt;, for those who need to download the image from a machine without Windows (my case! Yay!)... but when I entered the service tag, the page said there are no downloads available for my machine's model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other way is to contact support and request a physical copy of the media, and if the computer isn't under the warranty period (it isn't anymore), I have to pay around $60 USD! No thanks...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a last attempt, I found a &lt;a href="http://marcelosaldanha.com.br/2016/03/reinstalando-windows-sem-midia/"&gt;blog post (in Portuguese) by someone with a similar problem&lt;/a&gt;, where I learned of a &lt;a href="https://techjourney.net/official-windows-10-8-1-7-iso-installation-media-download-links-microsoft-tech-bench/"&gt;workaround&lt;/a&gt; to download Windows 7 directly from Microsoft's servers without the need to inform the serial code. Basically it's a page to download Windows 10 (which doesn't ask for a serial code to provide the download link), except that if you change a parameter in the URL that corresponds to the product Windows 10 for the one corresponding to Windows 7, the page would generate a Windows 7 download link. It's based on the API that manufacturers use to download the Windows installation media, and some people found out the IDs of all the possible ISOs. I Tried. And... it didn't work! I tried with the Windows 10 ID and it worked*, but for Windows 7, no luck. Apparently, this method isn't working for Windows 7 and Office. It seems that the workaround either doesn't work anymore, or there's a temporary problem with the API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* I got a Windows 10 download link, but I can't use it because I don't have a Windows 10 serial code to activate it if I install it. I don't even know whether Windows 10 would run on this machine...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow... dealing with proprietary software is so complicated! For now, I gave up. If the workaround resumes working, I may consider trying again another time. Meanwhile, I guess I'll have to resort to Wine and sighted assistance. Oh well...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installing the SSD&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday, January 8th, the SSD arrived. I had known it was smaller than a desktop PC HD, but I hadn't expected it to be so small and thin... it's as thin as a CD case, and looks like a glorified memory card (which it probably is :P ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mother and I opened the machine and swapped the dead HD out for the SSD. Unlike traditional HDs which have different sizes (3.5 inches for desktop PCs, and 2.5 inches for laptops), apparently there's only one SSD size, which is 2.5 inches. So, ideal for laptops, but a bit small for desktops (fortunately the SATA connections are the same). We plugged the SATA cable and attached the SSD to the case with a screw the way it should be done, but it wasn't as firm as we'd have liked. Ideally, I should've gotten a 2.5" to 3.5" adapter to fit the SSD easier, but the seller I bought the SSD from didn't have that, plus I was in a hurry because I needed my machine for work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people just plug the SSD and leave it hanging from the SATA cables inside the machine without much worry, since SSDs don't have moving parts like HDs, which means less risk of corrupting data from impact. But we got a bit worried. It didn't feel right to leave the SSD loose inside the machine. So, we cut an old and unused USB cable we had lying around, tied it to the "walls" of the compartment inside the case, to act like a "net" to help keep the SSD in place and prevent it from falling. It's ugly inside, but it works! :P Though I'm still wondering whether I should get one of those adapters to have a less "hackish" solution...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Partitioning the Disk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did once I turned the machine on was insert the Slint (talking) installer DVD, and checked the disk with Fdisk. The system recognized the SSD just fine, and the size was reported as 223 GiB, which translates to the advertised 240GB. Then I partitioned the disk, and ended with roughly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;84GB for Windows, in case I ever manage to reinstall it on this machine. If not, I'll use the precious space for something else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;84GB for the home partition, meant to be used by two Linuxes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4GB for swap. I don't recall this machine ever having resorted to swap, but who knows when the need may arise...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;34GB for my main system, Linux. Instead of installing Slackware, this time I decided to go with &lt;a href="http://slint.fr/wiki/en/start"&gt;Slint&lt;/a&gt;, a Slackware-based distro with accessibility out of the box (including a talking installer), though it's pretty much Slackware at its core.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And the last 34GB for the other Linux. I picked Arch Linux mostly because it also has a talking installer (in the form of the &lt;a href="https://talkingarch.tk/"&gt;Talking Arch ISO&lt;/a&gt;), and because I found out it's able to run the (closed-source proprietary and hard to troubleshoot) online banking software many of the banks in my country decided to adopt (I couldn't make it work on Slackware no matter what, and being unable to access the online banking was becoming a big problem. But the software worked nicely in the test Arch Linux install on my netbook, so...).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I installed Slint at night, and I was already able to use the machine for work the following day. That weekend, I installed Arch Linux and the Internet banking software into the other partition. After that, I've been slowly adjusting settings and installing extra things as the needs arise, in both Slint and Arch to make them behave the way I want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is the status at the time of this writing. Things are getting back to normal, better and faster, thanks to the SSD. The machine responds quicker than before and feels like new. And now we have access to the online banking as well. Having the HD break was quite the scare, but things seem to have changed for better. Maybe I've kicked off the year in a good note, after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to say that I had no issues while configuring the two Linux distros to make them my own, though. I had a few issues (mainly with Arch, and mostly thanks to my unfamiliarity with it), though most of them are solved by now. But that's a subject for another post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next post, I intend to talk about Slint, the Slackware-based, multi-language distro with accessibility out of the box and a talking installer!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/new-year-new-disk/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 19:00:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Server Migration and Blog System Change</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/static-blog-migration/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even though the blog's visual didn't change much, it's core has changed drastically. Now it's a static blog, with only HTML pages and doesn't need PHP or a database anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Why a Static Blog?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, static blogs work like this: I write posts in some markup language (I use &lt;a href="https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/"&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;) in a text editor of my choice, then a generator program (usually command line-driven) transforms posts into HTML and combines them with layout templates of the page (header, menu, content etc.) and generates all HTML pages, which can be uploaded to any webserver. For me, writing on my favorite text editor and typing a few simple commands to generate and upload the pages is much more comfortable than struggling for hours with a heavy web interface full of JavaScript (the reason why I never got along with WordPress).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been a while since I've been wanting to migrate to a static blog. I had tested several static blog generator programs, but none had exactly the features I wanted (mainly multilanguage content support). I had even started trying to program my own (in Perl), but in the end, I gave up. Then, this year (2015), I found this software called &lt;a href="https://getnikola.com/"&gt;Nikola&lt;/a&gt; (which is written in Python). A few tests later, I concluded that it does everything I want (and then some), and decided that the time to migrate had come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;And Why the Server Change?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been hosting my sites at &lt;a href="http://www.dreamhost.com/r.cgi?362621"&gt;DreamHost&lt;/a&gt; since 2007 and never had any problems. Particularly, I rather like the &lt;a href="http://wiki.dreamhost.com/"&gt;great documentation available on their wiki&lt;/a&gt;, SSH access which enables uploading files via Rsync instead of FTP (basically, it's faster because Rsync sends only what is different between the files on my machine and the ones on the server, rather than reuploading everything all over again), the ability to install other software on the server (the wiki provides detailed instructions), the ability to edit PHP settings, among other things, and last but not least, their humorous monthly newsletters :P. Then why did I decide to change webhosts? For a few simple reasons: even though all of these features are interesting, over the years I discovered I don't need this much. I don't have as much time to develop sites as I had before, when I signed up for their service in 2007. At the time, I still didn't have a job, and believed I'd work designing sites. Then, I got a job as a Perl programmer, years passed and, in the end, the only site I've been able to maintain (more or less) actively is this one you're on right now, and it barely used PHP and MySQL. Now that the site is static, I don't even need PHP and MySQL anymore! And with the high US Dollar rates (one Dollar nearing four Brazilian Reals), the hosting plan is getting hard to afford, and it doesn't make much sense to keep paying for so many features I'm not using. That said, even if I don't use the service anymore, I still consider DreamHost's webhosting very good, and I recommend it to those who don't have problems with the Dollar rates :P , and need a webhost that supports MySQL, PHP (or Perl or Python which are also included in their plan) and SSH access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domain registration for "warpstar.net" will still remain on DreamHost (not only because I like the included features like whoes privacy protection, but also because this serves as an excuse for me to keep receiving the humorous monthly newsletters :P *). But now, the blog is hosted on &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;, and the pages are uploaded via Git (which also only uploads the differences in the files rather than reuploading everything every time), and as a bonus, the site even got version control :D !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit: or so I had thought. The account cancel page says that if I cancel the hosting, even if I keep the domain registration, I won't get the newsletters anymore. Too bad... :(&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit (2016/03/04): apparently not! Despite what the cancel page said, I still keep receiving the newsletters :D !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasons above are important to me, but... okay, enough rambling. In the end, what really matters to everyone else is that all the content is here, the URLs remain the same, and the site is still online. The conversion may not have been 100%. There might be a few bugs here and there, and I intend to correct them as I find them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/static-blog-migration/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 18:11:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>In the Mood to DASH!</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-dash/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I began revisiting the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mega_Man_Legends"&gt;Rockman DASH (Mega Man Legends)&lt;/a&gt; series, watching (read "listening") some playthroughs and cutscenes to refresh my memory (I don't have the games anymore), trying to finally understand the plot. I didn't know enough of either Japanese or English to be able to grasp it at the time I played, which was some 12 years ago. Turns out that I can't fully figure it out even now :P. I have the impression that the second game (the one with the major plot points) felt a bit rushed, some important things are mentioned only in passing and aren't expanded anywhere. After the cancellation of DASH/Legends 3, it's unlikely that we'll be seeing these answers anytime soon. I also noticed differences between the dialogue from the English version and the original Japanese (inconsistencies in the translation/usage of names and terms) which may affect how we view a characters personality, as well as parts of the plot itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from that, I still think it's a good plot, albeit a bit confusing and full of unexplored potential. That calls to one thing: fan fiction!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After checking the playthroughs, then reading a few discussions and fan fictions to see how other people interpret the plot, I was inspired to write my own fanfic, intitled "&lt;a href="https://www.fanfiction.net/s/10564022/1/Trigger-of-Change"&gt;Trigger of Change&lt;/a&gt;". And like I did with my &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/pokemon/sl/drama"&gt;Pokemon fic&lt;/a&gt;, I began making Japanese anime style audio dramas out of it. This prompted the creation of a new &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/rockman"&gt;Rockman section&lt;/a&gt; on the site, with the page for the audio dramas &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/rockman/toc/drama"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude this post, I leave you with my VOCALOID cover of "Anata no Kaze ga Fuku Kara", the ending song to the first game. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download/listen: &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.opendrive.com/files/89882897_wjfA3_acdc/gumi_power_-_dash-kaze_0.1.ogg"&gt;OGG (OpenDrive)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.4shared.com/mp3/44Pq_-xLba/gumi_power_-_dash-kaze_01.html"&gt;MP3 (4shared)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zW77ScDa3hA"&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aiyumi, DASHing off!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><category>Site Updates</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-dash/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 18:51:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Pokemon Section</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/new-pokemon-section/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I added a new Pokemon section to the site, mostly to publish my music arrangements and the fan fic based audio dramas I already &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/twitter-and-updates"&gt;mentioned&lt;/a&gt;. To visit it, go &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/pokemon"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><category>Site Updates</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/new-pokemon-section/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 23:54:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Twitter and Updates</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/twitter-and-updates/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It may not seem like it, but a lot happened after my last post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did an arrangement of another music from Pokemon Black &amp;amp; White. It's the music titled "Ghetsis' Ambitions". Listen &amp;amp; download &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5eUh9bHd7aM"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://gobblin.se/u/aiyumi/m/pokemon-bw-arrange-of-ghetsis-ambitions-motif-xf/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably this is where I'm most active at the moment. I never mentioned it here before, but for some time now, I've been writing a Pokemon Black &amp;amp; White fan fiction (in English). It's called &lt;a href="http://www.fanfiction.net/s/8853146/1/"&gt;Soul Link&lt;/a&gt;, and I'm silently updating it regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did an audio drama adaptation of a scene from said fan fiction. The fanfic is in English, but the audio drama is in Japanese. The dialogue is mostly the same as the one from the fan fiction, so for those who understood the scene in the fic, the Japanese drama can probably be understood as well. A few people who like watching anime with Japanese audio might like it... Or not :P. Anyway, it can be found &lt;a href="https://gobblin.se/u/aiyumi/m/psl-ch004-true-plans/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It also uses the music arrangement I just mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I uploaded a few more sounds to &lt;a href="http://www.freesound.org/people/Aiyumi/"&gt;Freesound&lt;/a&gt;. I also added a lot of interesting sounds from other people to my &lt;a href="http://www.freesound.org/people/Aiyumi/bookmarks/"&gt;bookmarks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally got around to organizing my SlackBuilds for compiling Orca under Slackware and &lt;a href="https://github.com/aiyumi/slackware-scripts"&gt;uploaded them to Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit (2013-09-27): instructions on how to use the scripts now can be found &lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/installing-orca-on-slackware-14-0"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a 3DS XL. I wasn't thinking on doing that yet, but once again, I found a cheap one (for Brazil standards), and since prices in general are rising due to inflation, I decided to do it before it got too expensive. I won't make a full review like I did with the other one, but it suffices to say that compared to the normal 3DS, the buttons are more comfortable, the console is easier to hold (though a bit heavier) and the battery lasts more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In mid July, my internet connection stayed down for nearly two weeks, affecting my work and everything. Calling the ISP only resulted in pointless excuses most of the time, and it took very long for them to have the will to send a technician here and fix it. It was a problem affecting the whole region where I live. Hopefully it's sorted out now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I've been listening a lot of Japanese music which uses singing synthesis software like &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vocaloid"&gt;VOCALOID&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Utau"&gt;UTAU&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, a lot happened, as you can see. The problem is that I don't have the patience to write a full blog post for each thing I do, let alone in three languages... And I realized: isn't that the purpose of a microblog like Twitter? Right now, my Twitter isn't seeing much use aside from automatically alerting when I post something here. I'm thinking of making it update (preferably automatically) whenever I publish a fanfic chapter, or a Youtube video and maybe a few other things, so people can know I'm still active even if this blog isn't updated so often. The account is "&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/aiyumi_en"&gt;@aiyumi_en&lt;/a&gt;". You can follow me, or if you're like me and aren't much into these social network things, you can use this &lt;a href="http://www.rssitfor.me/getrss?name=aiyumi_en"&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><category>Site Updates</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/twitter-and-updates/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 18:39:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Adventures with a New Computer</title><link>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/adventures-with-a-new-computer/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My seven year old computer started to show signs of dying, so I bought a new one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Choosing a Machine&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I also needed to use the computer for work, I chose a little more "professional" machine. I bought a Dell Vostro 270S (Vostro 270 Slim) Desktop. Aside from work, I also need some fun, so I got the one with 1 TB hard drive and an off board video card, for running games and things that the old PC couldn't even dream of running. After some customizations, I got a computer with the following specifications: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/adventures-with-a-new-computer/"&gt;more…&lt;/a&gt; (5 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>http://aiyumi.warpstar.net/en/blog/adventures-with-a-new-computer/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 15:19:37 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>