<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Aiyumi.Github.Io (Posts about Site Updates)</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/tag/site-updates.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 Aiyumi &lt;a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/"&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:37:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Changed the Website's Layout at Last!</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/changed-layout-at-last/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;9 years later - yes, the blog started in 2011 -, I finally got around to changing the website's layout! The new layout is based on the &lt;a href="https://themes.getnikola.com/v7/yesplease/"&gt;Yesplease theme for the Nikola CMS&lt;/a&gt; with lots of modifications. It's a very barebones layout, but hopefully the text is easier to read. Unlike the previous layout, this one is responsive and should work better on small screens like on smartphones and tablets. Now the content is on the right, the menu is on the left and should be toggleable on small screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still intend to continue publishing most of my posts on the &lt;a href="https://hive.blog/@aiyumi"&gt;Hive social network&lt;/a&gt;, so I embeded the feed showing the links to my latest Hive posts on the main page. The only problem is that I had to use JavaScript for that (there was no other way because this is static site and has no support for any programming language like PHP), and nothing will change for those who use browsers with no JavaScript support (just visit my Hive profile page and view my posts there directly, just like it was before). I believe this shouldn't be much of a problem, though...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another improvement was in the post listing pages. Now these pages show a brief snippet of the posts, rather than only the title like it used to be. This applies both to the normal blog posts and the Hive posts on the front page! The listings should be more interesting this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is it for this update. See you in my next posts, either on Hive or on here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/changed-layout-at-last/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:36:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Time to Say Goodbye to the Warpstar.net Domain</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/goodbye-to-the-warpstar/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was alerted that the "warpstar.net" domain is going to expire if I don't renew the registration until May 13th, 2020. I get these alert messages every year, when it's one month from the domain registration anniversary. A few years ago, I had already &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/static-blog-migration"&gt;canceled the paid webhosting plan that was getting quite expensive to me&lt;/a&gt;, and this year, I decided it's time to let the paid domain go. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/goodbye-to-the-warpstar/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/goodbye-to-the-warpstar/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 23:41:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Status Update 2019/07/21</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/status-update-2019-07-21/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot has already happened in this year of 2019:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year's first half was particularly hard. My mother got sick, and we went through some tough times. For a few months, I had no time nor inspiration and wasn't in the mood to post anything anywhere, and sadly had to put my violin lessons on hold as well. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/status-update-2019-07-21/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/status-update-2019-07-21/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 23:43:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Two New Toys in the Kitchen</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/two-new-toys-in-the-kitchen/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/p3-food-ramen"&gt;post about ramen&lt;/a&gt;, I had talked about some of the obstacles I face in the kitchen, and that cooking isn't my cup of tea. But as evidenced by that post itself, sometimes crazy things happen when I decide to do something different... &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/two-new-toys-in-the-kitchen/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/two-new-toys-in-the-kitchen/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 23:42:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Small Status Update and a Post About Accessibility of Clickable HTML Elements</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/status-update-2018-07-20/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just passing by to show I'm still around :P . It's been a few months since I last posted anything here, but I still update my fan fiction every month. To my surprise, I've also been managing to be active on Steemit, posting at least once a week (twice if we consider I usually publish the same post both in Portuguese and in English). Incidentally, my last Steemit post was about the accessibility problems that happen a lot with clickable HTML objects, which may be of interest to anyone visiting my blog to read about accessibility. Below is the link to the post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://steemit.com/accessibility/@aiyumi/web-accessibility-clickable-objects-and-screen-readers"&gt;Web Accessibility - Clickable Objects and Screen Readers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find other posts on &lt;a href="https://steemit.com/@aiyumi"&gt;my Steemit blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/status-update-2018-07-20/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 17:35:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>My First Week on Steemit, and My First Impressions</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/steemit-first-impressions/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've never had much patience, nor luck, with social networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've tried to use twitter, but nothing came out of it. I didn't have the patience to read others' things and post constantly, and it was cumbersome to rephrase everything I wrote to fit the character limit. In the end, &lt;a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/aiyumi_en"&gt;my Twitter&lt;/a&gt; was relegated to just informing people about blog and fanfic updates. &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/steemit-first-impressions/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/steemit-first-impressions/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 13:47:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Year, New Disk</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/new-year-new-disk/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018 arrived, and I kicked off the year with... a hard drive failure in my main PC. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/new-year-new-disk/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (9 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/new-year-new-disk/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 19:00:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Server Migration and Blog System Change</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/static-blog-migration/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even though the blog's visual didn't change much, it's core has changed drastically. Now it's a static blog, with only HTML pages and doesn't need PHP or a database anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Why a Static Blog?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, static blogs work like this: I write posts in some markup language (I use &lt;a href="https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/"&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;) in a text editor of my choice, then a generator program (usually command line-driven) transforms posts into HTML and combines them with layout templates of the page (header, menu, content etc.) and generates all HTML pages, which can be uploaded to any webserver. For me, writing on my favorite text editor and typing a few simple commands to generate and upload the pages is much more comfortable than struggling for hours with a heavy web interface full of JavaScript (the reason why I never got along with WordPress).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been a while since I've been wanting to migrate to a static blog. I had tested several static blog generator programs, but none had exactly the features I wanted (mainly multilanguage content support). I had even started trying to program my own (in Perl), but in the end, I gave up. Then, this year (2015), I found this software called &lt;a href="https://getnikola.com/"&gt;Nikola&lt;/a&gt; (which is written in Python). A few tests later, I concluded that it does everything I want (and then some), and decided that the time to migrate had come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;And Why the Server Change?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been hosting my sites at &lt;a href="http://www.dreamhost.com/r.cgi?362621"&gt;DreamHost&lt;/a&gt; since 2007 and never had any problems. Particularly, I rather like the &lt;a href="http://wiki.dreamhost.com/"&gt;great documentation available on their wiki&lt;/a&gt;, SSH access which enables uploading files via Rsync instead of FTP (basically, it's faster because Rsync sends only what is different between the files on my machine and the ones on the server, rather than reuploading everything all over again), the ability to install other software on the server (the wiki provides detailed instructions), the ability to edit PHP settings, among other things, and last but not least, their humorous monthly newsletters :P. Then why did I decide to change webhosts? For a few simple reasons: even though all of these features are interesting, over the years I discovered I don't need this much. I don't have as much time to develop sites as I had before, when I signed up for their service in 2007. At the time, I still didn't have a job, and believed I'd work designing sites. Then, I got a job as a Perl programmer, years passed and, in the end, the only site I've been able to maintain (more or less) actively is this one you're on right now, and it barely used PHP and MySQL. Now that the site is static, I don't even need PHP and MySQL anymore! And with the high US Dollar rates (one Dollar nearing four Brazilian Reals), the hosting plan is getting hard to afford, and it doesn't make much sense to keep paying for so many features I'm not using. That said, even if I don't use the service anymore, I still consider DreamHost's webhosting very good, and I recommend it to those who don't have problems with the Dollar rates :P , and need a webhost that supports MySQL, PHP (or Perl or Python which are also included in their plan) and SSH access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domain registration for "warpstar.net" will still remain on DreamHost (not only because I like the included features like whoes privacy protection, but also because this serves as an excuse for me to keep receiving the humorous monthly newsletters :P *). But now, the blog is hosted on &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;, and the pages are uploaded via Git (which also only uploads the differences in the files rather than reuploading everything every time), and as a bonus, the site even got version control :D !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit: or so I had thought. The account cancel page says that if I cancel the hosting, even if I keep the domain registration, I won't get the newsletters anymore. Too bad... :(&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit (2016/03/04): apparently not! Despite what the cancel page said, I still keep receiving the newsletters :D !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasons above are important to me, but... okay, enough rambling. In the end, what really matters to everyone else is that all the content is here, the URLs remain the same, and the site is still online. The conversion may not have been 100%. There might be a few bugs here and there, and I intend to correct them as I find them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Site Updates</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/static-blog-migration/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 18:11:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>In the Mood to DASH!</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-dash/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I began revisiting the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mega_Man_Legends"&gt;Rockman DASH (Mega Man Legends)&lt;/a&gt; series, watching (read "listening") some playthroughs and cutscenes to refresh my memory (I don't have the games anymore), trying to finally understand the plot. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-dash/"&gt;Read the full article…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><category>Site Updates</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/in-the-mood-to-dash/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 18:51:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Pokemon Section</title><link>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/new-pokemon-section/</link><dc:creator>Aiyumi</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I added a new Pokemon section to the site, mostly to publish my music arrangements and the fan fic based audio dramas I already &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/twitter-and-updates"&gt;mentioned&lt;/a&gt;. To visit it, go &lt;a href="https://aiyumi.github.io/en/pokemon"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Audio</category><category>Fan-Made</category><category>Games</category><category>Site Updates</category><guid>https://aiyumi.github.io/en/blog/new-pokemon-section/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 23:54:43 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>